David C. Mahoney Company Records
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library
David C. Mahoney Company Records
1953-1969
Hartford History Center, Hartford Public Library Hartford, Connecticut
David C. Mahoney Company
2.25 linear feet
Real estate records including site plans and photographs for various properties in Hartford.
Historical Note
David C. Mahoney was born in 1903. In 1926, he opened a real estate office in New Britain, and from 1932 to 1945 he was director of Connecticut General Insurance Company’s real estate department. In 1945, he established the David C. Mahoney Company, later known as RLM Co., in West Hartford. An active member of the Hartford Real Estate Board, Mahoney advocated the rehabilitation of older buildings rather than demolition and slum clearance. Following his retirement, he moved to Delray Beach, Florida, where he died in 1987. The David C. Mahoney Collection was organized by Mahoney’s son, Richard Mahoney.
Scope and Content
The David C. Mahoney Collection in the Hartford History Center is primarily composed of records from the files of the David C. Mahoney Co., Inc., a West Hartford real estate company, documenting commercial and residential property in Hartford listed by the firm in the 1950s and 1960s. Buildings include houses, apartment buildings, restaurants, stores, office buildings, theaters, and other businesses. Most of the records include detailed descriptions, photographs of the structures, and site plans. Some of the photographs show parking lots, automobiles, billboards, and highways. Some contain letters addressed to Robert J. Bliss, director of the Hartford Redevelopment Agency. Many but not all of the properties were affected by urban renewal and some of the structures documented no longer exist. Additional photographs document buildings that were demolished during construction projects in the 1970s and 1980s. One box contains real estate maps which include the names of property owners and show the locations of many of the buildings represented in the collection.
Access Restrictions
The records are stored in a restricted area and therefore may not be available on a same-day basis.
Accruals
The collection is closed. Additional accruals are not expected.
Subject Headings
Personal Names
Bliss, Robert J.; Mahoney, David C.
Corporate Names
C.H. Dresser & Son; Case, Lockwood & Brainard Co.; Connecticut Printers; David C. Mahoney Company; Emhart Corporation; Hartford National Bank and Trust Company; Hartford Redevelopment Agency; Henry Souther Engineering Company; Heublein Hotel; McGovern Granite Company; Merrow Machine Company; Salvation Army; Underwood Typewriter Company
Subjects
Apartment houses; Automobiles; Billboards; Boarding houses; Commercial buildings; Dwellings; Factories; Garages; Highways; Hotels; Industrial buildings; Motion picture theaters; Parking lots; Real estate development; Real property--Maps; Real property--Valuation; Restaurants; Stores, Retail; Tenement houses; Theaters; Urban renewal; Warehouses
Genre Terms
Correspondence; Maps; Photographs; Site plans
Contents:
- Items
  - Allyn Street, See Trumbull Street, Southwest Corner (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 10-16 Allyn Street/247-273 Trumbull Street, 1968; Block #5, Parcel #15. Typescript description of block which housed stores, offices, and the City Club, with photocopies of photographs and site plan. (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 18-24 Allyn Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel #14. Typescript description, site plan, and photograph showing two stores, Betty's and Freed's. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 26-34 Allyn Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 13. Typescript description of building that included stores, apartments, offices; site plan and photograph showing Karen Studios, Mario Restaurant, and Kenneth Libby & Co. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 29-45 Allyn Street, See 192-200 Asylum Street. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 34-46 Allyn Street, 1964-1969; Block #5, Parcel #12. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing Perlmutter, Inc., a music store, and a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - 47-63 Allyn Street, 1966; Block #6, Parcel #3. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing the three-story brick store, office and loft building. (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 48-54-1/2 Allyn Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 11. Site plan and one photograph of the property, a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 63 Allyn Street, rear, 1966; Block #6, Parcel 4. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing a warehouse with a billboard for Geo. E. Dewey & Co. Moving and Storage and Christmas decorations on a lamp post. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 58-68 Allyn Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel #10. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing a warehouse and manufacturing building housing Harris Office Equipment and Stationery. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - 70-80 Allyn Street, See 230 Ann Street. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - 71 Allyn Street, See 240-242 Asylum Street. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - 160-164 Ann Street, See 250-256 Asylum Street. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - 174-182 Ann Street, See 240-242 Asylum Street. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - 230 Ann Street/70-80 Allyn Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel #9. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph showing a building housing a barber shop and a restaurant, Buster's Luncheonette. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - 1000 Asylum Street, ca. 1965; Illustrated brochure offering for lease the former National Fire Insurance Company building, which was subsequently occupied by The Security Insurance Company. (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - 139-147 Asylum Street, 1964; Block #7, Parcel #1. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph showing businesses including Kramer's Men's Clothing, Zacher's, and Melody Music. (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - 176-188 Asylum Street, 1964; Block #6, Parcel #2. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph showing E. M. Loew's Theater, Sol's Toys and Novelties and other stores; Herb's Sport Shop and Hartford Piano & Organ Co. are in an adjoining building. (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - 192-200 Asylum Street/29-45 Allyn Street, 1966; Block #6 Parcel #2. Typescript and four 35mm negatives showing a movie theater and stores. (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - 206-236 Asylum Street, 1966; Block #6, Parcel #7. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph showing the property, a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - 240-242 Asylum Street/174-182 Ann Street/71 Allyn Street, 1966; Block #6, Parcel #5. Typescript description, site plan, and four photographs showing Clinton's Pianos Organs; a restaurant, Capitol Luncheonette; and a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - 250-256 Asylum Street/160-164 Ann Street, 1966; Block #6, Parcel #6. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph showing the property, a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Asylum Street, northwest corner/Trumbull Street, 1964; Block #6, Parcel #3. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing the property, a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - 318-320 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plans of house and garage, and photograph of the wood frame three-family house. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - 326 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plan, and photograph of the house. (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - 334 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plan, and photograph of the house; according to the typescript the property included a small chicken coop. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - 344 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plans, and photograph showing a complex of buildings housing a. display room, office, shop, engine and winch house, storage building and a garage. (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - 344 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal of garage and shed owned by the McGovern Granite Company; one photograph showing the street front of the property. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - 378 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plans of house and garage, and photograph of the house. (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - 386 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plan, and photograph of the house; according to the typescript description, the property included a chicken coop. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - 394-396 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal, floor plans of house and garage, and photograph of the house. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - 404-410 Barbour Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and photograph of a vacant lot. (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Barbour Street rear, Cleveland Avenue, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and photograph of a vacant lot. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - 173 Bartholomew Avenue, 196-?; Site plan and photographs showing an industrial building and shed belonging to Emhart Corporation. (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Block 7 Parcel A/Trumbull Street/Pearl Street/Asylum street, 196-?; Block #7, Parcel A. Site plan; photograph showing an alleyway between two brick buildings with fire escapes. (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - 10-16 Charter Oak Avenue, 196-?; Block #6, Parcel 8. Typescript description and site plan. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - 18-24 Charter Oak Avenue, 1965; Block #6, Parcel 9. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph of street with and house and brick apartment building. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - 28 Charter Oak Avenue, 1960; Block #6, Parcel 10. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs of house and garage. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - 30 Charter Oak Avenue, ca. 1960?; Block #5, Parcel 31. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing house and garage. (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - 32 Charter Oak Avenue, ca. 1960?; Block #5, Parcel 31. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs showing house and garage. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - 34-36 Charter Oak Avenue, 1953; Block #5, Parcel 29. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph of the rooming house. (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - 38 Charter Oak Avenue, 195-?; Block #5, Parcel 28. Typescript description, site plan, and two photographs, one of a three-car garage and one of store with a sign that reads "Liszko." (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - 50-56 Charter Oak Avenue, See 103-105 Governor Street (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - 76 Charter Oak Avenue, 195-?; Block #3, Parcel 14. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of the house. (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - 82-84 Charter Oak Avenue, 195-?; Block #3, Parcel 15. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of the house and garage. (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - 86-92 Charter Oak Avenue, 195-?; Block #3, Parcel 16. Typescript description of Building #1, a tenement and rooming house, site plan of Buildings #1 and #2, and photographs of both buildings. (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - 96-104 Charter Oak Avenue/1 Union Street/2-4, 10-12 Union Street/307-337 Sheldon Street, 195-?; Block #2, Parcel 1. Site plan and five photographs and negatives showing brick tenement houses and Lombardo's Paramount service station. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - 108 Charter Oak Avenue, 1965; Brief typescript description and one photograph of a brick office building and parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Church Street Parking Company, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 4. Two site plans and nine photographs showing parking lot, billboards, and other advertising signs. (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - 18-20 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 11. Typescript description, site plan, and one photograph and negative of a commercial building housing Gloria Gay, a women's clothing store. (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - 26-30 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 12. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph and negative showing the Old Homestead, apparently a donut shop. (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - 36-48 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 13. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick commercial building housing Cutlery of Stengelin, Church's Shoes, and the Friendly Card Shop. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - 50-58 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 14. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph showing a brick commercial building housing Foley Travel and other businesses, with the Skillet Restaurant in an adjoining building. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - 62-72 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 15. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph showing a brick commercial building housing Belltone Hearing Aids, a Fabric Shop, the Skillet Restaurant, and Spencer's. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - 62-72 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 15. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph showing a brick commercial building housing Belltone Hearing Aids, a Fabric Shop, the Skillet Restaurant, and Spencer's. (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - 78-82 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 16. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph showing the Mayeda Oriental Gift Shop. (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - 79 Church Street, 1966; Block #5, Parcel 8. Typescript description, two site plans and one photograph of a parking lot and a brick Y.W.C.A. building. (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - 96-112 Church Street, See 306-318 Trumbull Street. (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - 90-92 Church Street, 1964; Block #1, Parcel 17. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a commercial building housing Connecticut Furriers. (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - 97-103 Church Street, See 270-290 Trumbull Street. (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - 134-146 Church Street, See 305-315 Trumbull Street (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - 135-142 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 1. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of Penthouse Beauty Studios in a brick commercial building with a billboard on the roof. (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - 157-159 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 2. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of Ken's Luncheonette and Donut Shop. (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - 161-163 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 3. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick building housing Central Realty Co. and Monach Photo Service & Supplies. (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - 169 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 4. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick rooming house building. (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - 171-173 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 5. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick store and tenement building. (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - 179-211 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 6. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of a parking lot and brick store building housing the Modern Blue Print Co., One Hour Martinizing and Dry Cleaning, and Yale Supplies. (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - 219 Church Street, 1964; Block #5, Parcel 7. Site plan and one photograph of a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Church Street, East, See Main Street, West. (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - City of Hartford, Tract #1, 196-?; City of Hartford, Tract #1. Brief typescript and three photographs of land bordering an elevated highway, used as a parking lot. (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - 219 Church Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and one photograph of a lot with two sheds. (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - 175 Cleveland Avenue, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and one photograph of a vacant lot. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - 177 Cleveland Avenue, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and one photograph of a vacant lot. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - 201 Cleveland Avenue, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and one photograph of a vacant lot. (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - 207 Cleveland Avenue, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal and one photograph of a lot with two sheds. (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Columbus Boulevard, See Sheldon Street, northwest corner (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - 132-136 Columbus Boulevard, 1967; Brief typescript description and one photograph of the City Fish Market. (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Underwood Redevelopment Project, comparable sales and rentals, 1953-1962; Typescript descriptions and photographs of 254 Putnam Street, 30 Willow Street, 41 Woodbine Street, 52 Laurel Street, 37 Woodbine Street, 124 Babcock Street, 64-66 Babcock Street, 165-167 Russ Street, 66 Lawrence Street, 46-48 Babcock Street, 40 Willow Street, 250 Putnam Street, 73 Babcock Street, 188 Russ Street, 9-11 South Woodbine Street, 148-150 Putnam Street, 97-99 Putnam Street, 55 Babcock Street, 107-109 Babcock Street, 160 Russ Street, 114-116 Babcock Street, 183-185 Babcock Street, 245 Putnam Street, 189-191 Russ Street, 126-128 Babcock Street, 170-172 Putnam Street, 123-125 Lawrence Street, 22-24 Mortson Street, 18-20 Putnam Heights, 6-8 Putnam Heights, 34-36 Mortson Street, 59 Grand Street. (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - 25 Elm Street, 1965; Brief typescript and photograph of a parking lot. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Elm Street, south; Main Street, west, 1965; Brief typescript and photograph of a parking lot. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - 80 Farmington Avenue, 1958; Typed coversheet of an appraisal report and photograph of a modern office building beside a Colonial revival building. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - 45 Gold Street, 1950; Block #1, Parcel 2. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a branch bank building and a parking lot. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - 103-105 Governor Street/50-56 Charter Oak Avenue, 1965; Brief typescript and photograph of a parking lot. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - 104-108 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 23. Typescript description, site plan and three photographs of a brick tenement building and two machine shops. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - 107 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 26. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of a frame multiple-family dwelling, driveway and garage. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - 111-113 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 25. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a frame multiple-family dwelling. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - 114-116 Governor Street, 1955; Block #4, Parcel 22. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of a parking lot and a small brick store building. (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - 120 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 18. Typescript description, site plan and three photographs of a multiple-family dwelling and a garage and storage area. (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 126 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 17. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of a brick multiple-family dwelling and garage. (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 128-130 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 15. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of a brick garage and a brick multiple-family dwelling and store housing Eddie's Market. (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 129-131 Governor Street, 1957; Block #5, Parcel 10. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick multiple-family dwelling. (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 133-134 Governor Street, See 143-149 Sheldon Street. (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 134 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 14. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs of a brick multiple-family dwelling and garage. (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 143 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 9. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick tenement building. (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 145 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 8. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of brick tenement building. (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - 136-138 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 11. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick multiple-family dwelling. (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - 140-142 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 10. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick warehouse and store, the Sechtman Hardware Company. (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - 144-146 Governor Street, 1955?; Block #4, Parcel 6. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick multiple-family dwelling. (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - 147 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 7. Short typescript description, site plan and one photograph of brick tenement buildings on a tree-lined street. (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - 149 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 6. Short typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a tenement building on a tree-lined street. (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - 150-156 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #4, Parcel 5. Short typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick tenement building with stores on the first floor. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - 151 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 5. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a brick tenement building on a tree-lined street. (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - 153 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 4. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a two brick tenement buildings. (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - 155 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 3. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a row of brick tenement buildings. (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - 157 Governor Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 2. Typescript description, site plan and one photograph of a row of brick tenement buildings. (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - 158-160 Governor Street, See 189-195 Sheldon Street. (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - 159-161 Governor Street/151 Sheldon Street, 1957?; Block #5, Parcel 1. Typescript description, site plan and two photographs showing a brick tenement building and a storefront housing Ted's Cleaners. (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - 69 Grove Street, 1966; Tract #1. One-page typescript with photograph of a street and parking lot. (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - 83 Grove Street, 1966; Tract #1. One-page typescript with photograph of a street and parking lot. (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Hartford office and warehouse, 195-?; Five photographs of a brick warehouse. (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Kensington Street, 1959; Typescript real estate appraisal with three photographs of a vacant lot with apartment buildings in the background. (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - 11 Laurel Street, 1965; Typescript description, site plan one and photograph of a brick factory, laboratory, and office building belonging to the Henry Souther Engineering Company. (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - 20 Laurel Street, 1962; Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan and one photograph of gasoline service station with a second-floor apartment. (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - 33-35 Laurel Street, 1962; Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan and one photograph of two six-family dwellings and a small store. (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - 34-36 Laurel Street, 1965; Typescript description and four negatives and photographs of six-family dwellings; sketch plan of building, site plan, and two photographs of property of the Merrow Machine Company. (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - 37 Laurel Street, 1962; Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan and one photograph of single-family house with attached store with a sign that reads "Home Circle Stores." (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - 41-53 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #3, Parcel 5. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan, and one photograph of a frame multiple-family dwelling. (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - 42 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #2, Parcel 20. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan showing house and two garages, and one photograph of the house. (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - 46 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #2, Parcel 19. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan showing house and garage, and one photograph of the house. (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - 52 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #2, Parcel 18. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan, and one photograph of a house. (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - 57 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #3, Parcel 4. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan, and one photograph of a house. (Box 2, Folder 44)
  - 56-58 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #2, Parcel 15. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan, and one photograph of a brick multiple-family dwelling. (Box 2, Folder 45)
  - 62 Laurel Street, 1962; Block #2, Parcel 14. Typescript real estate appraisal, site plan, and one photograph of a house. (Box 2, Folder 46)